## ALEXANDER WOLFGANG SIEGFRIED

484-788-1741 | awsiegfried@gmail.com | Tarzana, CA, 91356 | linkedin.com/in/awsiegfried | awsiegfried.herokuapp.com | github.com/AWSiegfried

Full-stack web developer leveraging a background in business development for early-stage Silicon Beach ad-tech startups. Technical proficiency coupled with business-side acumen and understanding of client desires. Innovative problem-solver, passionate about developing web applications with a progressive and eye-catching yet user-experience-focused design. Strengths in creative problem solving, organizational processes, and efficient execution of tasks.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, ES6+, CSS3, HTML5

**Technical:** React, Redux, MySQL, MongoDB, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Node.js, Express, jQuery, JSCharting, Bootstrap, Algorithms, Responsive Design, Material UI, Netlify, React-Google-login, User Authentication, MERN, Regex, Ajax, Axios **Competencies:** brand strategy, brand building, competitor analysis, campaign management/optimization, lead generation, conversion funnels, performance analytics, Pay-Per-Click, budgeting, retargeting, A/B testing, social media analytics, business development, prospecting, networking, contracts, CRM, Salesforce, Hubspot, Shopify, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop

#### **PROJECTS**

## Store Front | https://github.com/DJ620/store-front-react | https://storefrontreact.herokuapp.com/

A content management system that allows users to dynamically create a fully functional customized eCommerce website with checkout in less than 5 minutes.

- Co-developed a user-friendly, intuitive, and secure website with interactive features to optimize the user experience.
- Role: Heavily utilized React and Redux and aided back-end architecture.
- Tools: React, Redux, Redux-persist, Node, MySQL, Express, Cloudinary, Multer, Bootstrap

# HARMony | https://github.com/TChristensenDrumz/HARMony | harmonythegame.herokuapp.com

A web application combat-based video game with protected routes and full user-authentication. Written in HTML Canvas utilizing React components.

- Led a team of 5 to design, develop, debug, and deploy the web application in under two weeks.
- Full-stack developer: developed React components, game theory/logic, back-end database architecture, and front-end design.
- MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node), Passport, JSON web tokens)
- Role: Project manager, general styling director, game logic, game design, back-end database routing
- Tools: Canvas, React, Mongoose, JSONwebtoken, Robo 3T, Tiled, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Heroku

#### EMERGENCE | https://github.com/AWSiegfried/Emergence v1 | awsiegfried.github.io/Emergence v1

A web application that finds new local emerging artists by city. User searches for a genre and is returned a dynamically created artist overview that gives the user a complete perspective of a band in under 30 seconds using pulled data and visible metrics.

- Completed the web application in less than one week collaborating remotely using Zoom and Slack
- Identified, analyzed, and dynamically rendered complex data analytics
- Role: Team lead, front-end designer, and back-end API developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Heroku, Spotify API, Youtube API, JSCharting

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Smarty LLC, Senior Manager - Partnerships: Sherman Oaks, CA

May 2019 - July 2020

Established direct partnerships with company affiliate programs thus improving Smarty user experience. Partnerships included Expedia, Priceline, Verizon, QVC, Costco, Kmart, Michael Kors, etc.

- Developed and managed publisher partnerships increasing the total number of users by 150%.
- Partnered with nonprofit organizations to improve Smarty brand image, installs, and donations for the NPO.
- Signed advertising clients to market their products and services via our extension traffic.
- Developed and managed client's advertising campaigns averaging \$10,000/day.

## Klickly, Business Development Manager: Santa Monica, CA

August 2017 - May 2019

Successfully coordinated and headed the 2019 growth plan, reaching an evaluation of \$10MM with a zero-dollar budget.

- Created and maintained a year-long execution plan with bi-weekly goals and quotas.
- Expanded and oversaw sales channels, product development, and resources for the 2019 year.
- Orchestrated and executed client growth strategy: established and retained partnerships with other eCommerce businesses to increase annual recurring revenue by \$1MM, head of email marketing strategy, onboarded clients to the platform utilizing the CRM Streak.
- Trained and mentored a 2-5 person team of interns.

#### Circle for Roommates, Associate: West Hollywood, CA

**April 2017 - July 2017** 

Achieved 200% user growth in the first and second month; surpassed expected quotas thereafter.

- Implemented new initiatives for online and guerrilla marketing while ensuring the two align.
- Monitored and analyzed daily growth analytics using the programs Branch and Instabug.
- Assisted in developing sales pitches for future angel investors. Pitched to several potential investors.

## **EDUCATION**

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development: UCLA

October 2020-January 2021

Bachelor of Arts, Sociology and Minor in Music Industry: UCLA